called Order of the Regular Schedule Meeting of the Minor City Council for Monday, July 18, 2022.
Number two, Proclamation declaring of the honorary co-naming of West Central Avenue as Willie Osborne Drive.
Let's see you back from the family here to the present seat.
I'll need a motion if we want to approve that.
Second.
Okay.
I believe that there's going to be done during the festival on Saturday morning.
We're on the bullet run.
That's great.
Yep.
So if you want to be at that honor of street and renaming, it'll be,
whether it's quarter of a central name.
Central and A isn't it?
Central and A.
Yep.
Number three, Proclamation recognizing recognition of outstanding community service,
Mr. Ron stole.
And Mr. stole probably taught everybody that's setting up here.
They'll one time or another except for Ben.
Hey, thank you for your time here.
You haven't taught her, Mr. Ron?
He probably drove some choir trip.
That's right.
What did you do?
Oh, yeah.
So we have a Proclamation for you.
Mr. stole.
You raised the retired from my book, the schools after 51 years of teaching.
Wow.
Amazing.
That's quite a feat.
It went by pretty quickly.
Did it.
So we've got a Proclamation here for you guys.
When we come down a little bit.
I guess we have about to approve this or not.
It would be nice.
Oh, two.
Thank you.
So I don't say that.
All right.
Oh, we're here.
I guess we do.
All right, guys.
Let's look this side.
Appreciate it.
Thank you.
I'm three, oh, no, we just did three, four.
Public input runs, get the personal appearances.
We have nine, five, consider gender,
staff recommends we approve nine and six and seven.
You can move from my proof.
Say it.
Hi.
Dagestan.
Sunberg.
Hi.
Parker.
All right, budget amendment, 22-33 Street State
and utility improvement, general administrative
expanding for agent fees.
Mr. Mackay.
Yes, on our current law
we have for street and stadium and utility improvement
on, for charge agent fees on those.
We normally get two weeks here.
It was the invoice this late last year.
We had already closed the book.
So we had an extra one in this year.
So the funds weren't spent last year.
And we even spent extra funds this year to pay the third invoice
for that 20th this year.
The funds are in the account.
So we just need to be able to have.
Make a motion we approve.
Okay.
Is that, David?
Yes.
Don't go.
Hi.
Sunberg.
Parker.
Hi.
Thanks, Mike.
Sorry, just FYI on your ODOT reimbursements.
Once we submit the invoice to the cheeses, we let them go from
May to the budget.
Thank you.
Mr. McNeill.
and they've never been able to even through joint efforts between tribes, county, and city,
been able to come up with the funding.
So as Commissioner Earl stated, this was really a golden opportunity using the
ARPA funds that county has.
They wanted to initiate this project.
So with the city, this project will put air conditioning at the expo building.
You would also place it at an elevation that would be above floodplain or above past floods.
He was telling me today that the elevation would be above what the 2007 flood was.
So that it would be flood resilient and wouldn't get ruined in future floods in the event.
We moved from that location.
We could take the air conditioners with us.
Of course, we know this facility is used today for the fair, farmers market,
wedding problems.
It would actually give us another rentable space or venue here in the area.
And it is absolutely no match required.
So it's essentially free money for us to upgrade the expo.
This agreement that you all are looking at today is not a notice to proceed,
but would simply acknowledge the city's desire to move forward to this project
and utilize these funds from the county.
And there would be a subsequent contract identified spelled out
that would have any terms or conditions of the agreement.
That's it.
That sounds like a no-brainer.
I mean, the only question I have is obviously it's a no-brainer,
but you said that once we approve this little go through and then we will,
it will be put out for bid by for those who want to bid on it.
Yes.
So now they know how much we have.
Could we do that to expand all the funds?
Still negotiate.
It's interesting.
I wonder if we can do that for the bid.
Correct.
It would be our funds.
Yes.
So, say it's 100,000.
What happened with that 100?
It has to be spent out there.
Yes.
It would have to be spent for the project as identified in the grant.
In the expo building or anywhere on the very ground.
I think in the expo building.
Since that's the way I believe it was spelled out in the grant.
So what he funds not expended would go back to.
Yeah.
More to go.
I've been going to that facility since 1975.
Yes.
And I recall no condition there.
It's like there isn't the bathrooms there.
Right?
In the office.
Yeah.
Can't even know what to do with that.
There.
Yeah.
But I don't think the bathrooms were even always in there either.
No.
And they got a little bit of a different thing.
They think those were added.
Man, the pigs and chickens are going to be happy.
I know the farmers market girls would be happy.
Which we got the big fans in there.
So if you got some AC in there and those fans would be with that air.
It would be really comfortable in there.
Yes.
So are you needing a motion from us to proceed?
Yeah.
There's actually an agreement that we would sign that would allow them to move forward transferring the funds.
But, again, we still have a contract that we've all worked with.
All right.
I'll second.
Five.
Parker.
All right.
Five.
Davis.
All right.
East.
Ten.
Mayor's nomination to re-appoint Joe Del Morgan to the Monument
Downtown Redevelopment Authority Board.
Time to expire seven to 25.
Second.
East.
Five.
11.
Mayor's nomination to re-appoint Lynn Forkham to the Monument
Downtown Redevelopment Authority Board.
Time to expire eight twenty nine twenty five.
Second.
So.
Five.
Twelve.
Mayor's nomination to re-appoint Brenda Sears.
The Monument Housing Authority Board.
Time to expire one three to twenty five.
Motion.
East.
Five.
So.
Thirteen.
Mayor's nomination to re-appoint Becky Beard.
To the Monument Public Library Board.
Time to expire eight six of twenty five.
Five.
Fourteen.
Other new business of any, which is a residence in the
First of all, this agenda.
Fifteen.
Mayor and council community announcements.
Um.
By the way.
We got the root six to six festival coming up.
Um.
Not just coming weekend, but the following weekend.
And.
Some me hot.
But we've got some stuff playing to try to help you.
People cool.
We got some street re-naming.
All right.
And then one.
This will be re-naming.
Um.
Barbecue cook off.
We got a two time champion come to the barbecue cook off.
It sounds like a pretty good deal.
But it's a name.
You may remember.
Just.
You may remember his name.
Uh.
But I guess he's.
I guess he's from all of these.
It's two time champion on the pit boss.
Doers up to.
Uh.
I guess it's pretty big deal.
There's.
Stop.
So.
You know.
Yeah.
First.
Um.
And I think he's bringing a couple of people, with him.
Couple of the teams.
He's.
So.
Pretty cool.
For the first time to have them.
And I think for the.
Back yard barbecue.
We've got.
Eight teams.
They're right.
I think it's what.
Chan.
Um.
So.
Pretty cool.
The first time.
Um.
So.
We have a free movie at the Column that day for families.
Thanks to Chad Masterson.
Yes.
Options are running the movie for the kids.
Some cool stuff happening.
Of course.
Yeah.
So just kind of keep growing each year.
It seemed like the new stuff was added in.
So when our firefighters are having a cornhole turn them again.
So a lot of stuff going on that day.
Well, how we can invest?
16 cm communications.
Nope.
Just to reiterate.
It's going to be a great time.
It's going to be hot.
It's going to be hot for the next two weeks.
We need to all be sensitive to that.
All the folks in our community check on your neighbors.
Make sure we're checking after the elderly and those that are homebound.
The library during normal business hours, which is the heat of the day, is available as a cooling station.
Obviously, they have water and bathrooms and seating.
They're more than happy to have folks that.
If they're stuck in a hot house situation or have air conditioning problems, or don't have one.
And they need to get out.
They're more than welcome to come to the library and get some cooler air and cool down and stay safe.
And, you know, watch out for all of our folks.
Obviously, first responders that are out in the heat.
All of our folks that work outside do construction.
Those are tough jobs this time of year and in this heat.
It can be dangerous.
So, be respectful, be careful.
Make sure workers are being safe.
We're certainly putting the word out to city staff.
We're modifying hours where we need to.
Park staff is coming in extremely early.
Trying to avoid the heat of the day.
So they're starting their days very, very early.
But they're gearing up, obviously.
They're starting to focus on downtown and make sure that we've got our main street.
And they street and Steve Owens cleaned up and looking nice for the festival.
Hopefully all of our out of town guests that will be joining us that weekend.
I think we'll be putting our best foot forward.
Looking forward to the weekend.
Still a lot of work to do and try to stay safe in the seat.
So, Dean, adjourned.
So, move.
Second.